<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An Essay upon excisi[n]g several branches that have hitherto escaped the duty of the brewing trade to make good the deficiency of the malt-tax, and other funds</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 66 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 27 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A38639</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13254489</idno>
  <idno type="VID">98672</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240857825</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E3298</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R8609</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">13254489</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A38639)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 98672)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 453:19)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An Essay upon excisi[n]g several branches that have hitherto escaped the duty of the brewing trade to make good the deficiency of the malt-tax, and other funds</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>39 (i.e. 51) p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Malt --  Taxation.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-01 </date>
            <label>Alexis (Ali) Jakobson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-01 </date>
            <label>Alexis (Ali) Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title">
            <pb facs="tcp:98672:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:98672:1"/>
            <p>AN ESSAY UPON Excisi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>g several Branches that have hitherto Escaped the Duty of the <hi>Brewing Trade</hi> To make good the Desiciency of the Malt-Tax, And other FUNDS.</p>
            <p>Humbly Offered to the Consideration of the PARL<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>AMENT.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="essay">
            <pb facs="tcp:98672:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:98672:2"/>
            <head>An <hi>ESSAY</hi> upon Excising several Branches that have hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therto escap'd the Duty in the Brewing-Trade, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THe Gentleman that worte an Essay upon the Excising of Malt, and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so the Person that proposed the lay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing an Equal Tax upon Ale and Beer, at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempted, I find, to make the following just Observations, That nothing seems more to hinder the growth of the Duty of Excise, or contributes more to the ruining the Brewing-Trade, then the unreasonable Advantages that the overgrown Brewers are suffered, Undiscern'd, to enjoy, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove the poor and Industrious Managers of that part of the Trade, which now with a considerable share of the Kings Duty, lies ready to sink, and fall a Sacrifice to the Unlimited Power, and Magnificent way of the great Brewers Living. But it could not indeed be expected, that those Gentlemen, who were never Concern'd
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:98672:3"/>in the Brewing-Trade, and had no other grounds but what the Voice of Fame, or Messenger of Fancy brought 'em, should be capable of Proposing any Method or Advantage to the Government or Trade, that may not in some other Kind be destructive to it. But every unexpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rienced Person in this Case, is like one that gazes at a Comet, which he can reach with nothing but his Eye alone; so they see the splendid Lustre of the Brewers, but can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not tell how to direct the Goverment to touch their proper share, without dash<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing upon greater Inconveniences; which we find by Experience to have done, by the shrinking of the first Duty of Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cise, when the Additional one was laid on; and likewise have met with as fatal Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sequence by the General Tax laid upon Malt: But give me leave to tell you, that it is the wrong placing of a Tax, and not the weight, that works ill Effects in this Trade. Therefore to recover the decay'd part, and the Kings Duty, that must Infallibly sink with it, we should in some measure Copy after the Exam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of the skillful Physician, who to establish the Health of his Patient, do's not Let him Blood in every Part alto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, but wisely Breaths those Veins that he believes will conduce most to the Health of the Body; so in this Case
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:98672:3"/>we should not to that part of the Trade that lyes Languishing, take too much of its strength away by a General Tax, but Administer those sharp Coro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sives to a stronger Part, which in a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle time will work good Effects, by Esta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blishing the Health and Profits of both. But before I make any farther, progress, it's my humble Opinion, that that Person must needs be a very unskilful Discern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er of the Profits of the Brewing-Trade, that made no distinction between the Taxing of strong Beer and Ale, or the Quantities of Drink that are week<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Brewed by the great and small Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wer. And the next Undertaker, I am sure, wanted, no less a penetrating Judgment, that advised the laying a Tax equally upon Malt, except he was first satisfied, that the Profits of the several Persons which it was charg'd upon, were equal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly able to bear it: but I perceive their Notion of it much resembles that of a Mans discovering a rich Mine, fancies where it is, but cannot yet find out the right Vein, so diggs every where at a venture. But if after so many Baulks you can be now satisfied with the sufficiency of your Guide, I humbly hope to lead you to this long lookt for Treasure, where your expectation shall, I am sure, no longer lie wrapt in Uncertainties, provided you
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:98672:4"/>will by the following just Measures be pleased to level the great inequality that appears in the Profits of the rich and poorer sort of Brewers, whom they ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit of going sharers with them in nothing besides the Misfortune of being equally Taxt; by which means, and the great Brewers severe and cruel Usage to 'em, a very considerable part of the Trade is sunk and decay'd, and the Duty of Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cise dwindled away with it. But I humbly hope, the Measures by which I propose to Levy this Tax, will prevent that mighty Abuse that at present attends the Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing-Trade, even to the preservation of a great number of lesser Brewers, that strug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gle under great Difficulties in a Trade that the Government has received very large Supplies from, together with the advantage of producing and raising the King Four Hundred Thousand Pound <hi>per An.</hi> without advancing a Farthing more upon the Buyer, Consumer, or Retailer, nor even lessening the setled Profits of the Brewers, but onely take off some lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle small Edgings of what they are going to Enterlace their Fortunes with by un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>expected great Profits, which I will make appear is now flowing in upon them by the great Fall of Malt, Hops, Coals, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>k, and Rise of Drink, and by the Profits of the Trade being drawn to a
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:98672:4"/>Corner, and Ingrossed all in their own Hands; the Consideration of which, when well weighed, may, I think, ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der any Man Astrologer enough to foretel the Condition of the great Brewer, whose Interest was ever distinct from the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Good of the Trade and Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment: But what we are about, I hope, will frustrate their long premeditated De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sign, of putting the Trade in as bad a Condition as they can, purely to Mono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>polize it all in their own Hands, and to oblige the Parliament, by a seeming decay of it, to lighten the Taxes; and having gained their Point in that, are re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>solved, that Tyranical Power which has so long gnaw'd upon the small Brewers, shall now swallow 'em up quite, having nothing else to subdue that can keep them from getting above the reach of Fortune, but that, and liberty to Cramp and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tract the most flourishing Trade in the World, as they see fit, to square it to their own Stocks and and Conditions; After which, and that they have by their Warrants forced the small Brewers from their Trades, the next thing that fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows their Arbitrary Power will be, to Administer the Oath of Allegiance, which is to be True to their own Interest, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out admitting the least thought of a Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Good, or any regret for the great A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buse
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:98672:5"/>and Hardship put upon the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, which I will in its proper Place make appear, will in a few Months in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sensibly lose half the Duty of Excise, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept prevented by the following Expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dients, and also Treble their own Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits, by making them safe as well as great, when they have out of the whole Trade pickt and cull'd as many Customers as their stock and Condition can well Manage, therefore resolve not any longer to serve the poorer sort of Victuallers, who they have all their Lives made Slaves, and at last cut their Throats into the Bargain; in which sad Condition those unhappy Wretches, having no small Brewers to fly to for Credit, and not prepared to live innocently Poor, are therefore forced from their Industrious Course of Life, to turn High-way-Men, and such other desperate Attempts, to keep themselves from perishing; by which Means four several sorts of People are Ruined, <hi>viz.</hi> The small Brewer, whole shoales of them being forced by the op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pression of the great ones, to give over. And next, the Landlord of those Victuallers, whose Houses, by that means, lie waste. Thirdly, the Country, for letting those necessitous Creatures break loose upon them. Lastly and Chiefly, the King, who is every way depriv'd of his Taxes, and
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:98672:5"/>Subjects too, by putting the Laws in Execution against them; which I do not doubt, but it will be thought a hard Case, that so great a part of the King's Duty, and the vast numbers of poor Souls that rais'd it, should fall a Sacri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice to the undermining Stratagems, and unheard of Cruelties, that are used by those Marcenary People, to swell their own Heaps, and support their Extrava<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gant Way of Living, and all this Destru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction committed under a colourable Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of their Charter, from whence they derive that wicked Authority. But I hope we may put a stop to their Cariere, and by taking a little pains to seperate the Sheep from the Goats, be able to track home the Profits of the Trade to the right Owners doors, and not drive them all, as we hitherto have done, into the same Current together; which I que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stion not, but you will agree to be the chief Occasion of our loss and decay of Trade, when I lay before you, stript of all disguise, the vast Advantages the great Brewers have over the lesser in their way of Management, and likewise the extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vagant Profits which those Sparks have by their Beer Brewings; by which Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular several of them have from the Drays side, in a few Years, rais'd them selves from little or nothing to the Tune
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:98672:6"/>of Thousands, which well they may, when they crush and keep under all those of a later standing, and can with the same Charge of House-Rent and Servants Wages, bating those nimble broad-shoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derd Fellows, that are kept to carry off the concealed Drink from the Duty of Excise, Brew five times the quantity the small Brewer do's, with the advantage al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so of drawing half a Barrel of strong Drink more of each quarter of Malt, by reason of the bigness of his Grist, then the small Brewer can, having little beside the Tunstaves to work upon; and his Drink notwithstanding this shall be so much stronger, that he still gets the start of him, by defrauding in another kind the King of great part of his Duty, by putting of small Beer, to avoid the Penalty of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crease of Tun, first into his Barrels, and fil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling up the Ale after the Gauger is gone, to it, which the small Brewer can have no such Advantage, by reason a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modity drawn from so little a quantity is so poor at best, that it cause the fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quent Returns of his Drink, when com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pared by the Victualler to the high Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Liquors of the happier Brewer; and is made farther unfortunate, by being obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged to pay the Duty of Excise over again for those Returns, if he makes use or breaks them into his Tun among the
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:98672:6"/>rest of his Guile: But this Hardship th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> great Brewers are not so liable to, by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son the Strength and Goodness of their Drink still keeps Possession of the Victuallers Cellar; therefore in every respect has the better of the small Brewer, whose unhap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piness is still greater, being not able to give Credit, having it not himself, or Brew that Inriching Commodity of Hopt and Guile Beer, which yields the Brewer, as I shall in its proper place make appear Profits un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sufferable to think of. But the farther we in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spect into Matters of this nature, the great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er disparity still appears in the Gains of the small and great Brewer, who by the Reputation and rich Character he bears, is in a Morning rather Besieged than At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended by a Company of Malsters and Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors, who at first sight all start fair at him, to see who can use the best Rheto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rick for his Custom, while the proorer sort of Brewers, by following them, and their sheepish Looks together, are soon discover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to have no ready Money in their Pock<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ets, which causes the Malster to inhance his Price to that unreasonable degree, that he resolves his Commodity shall first be so well squees'd into his own Purse, that there shall be lttile left for such Buyers to drain after him, tho' at the same time he will let the great Brewer have as long Credit as he please<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, at least Two shillings
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:98672:7"/>in the Pound cheaper, and two more in the Pound better; so as that the greater Fish still devours the lesser, the able Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er by affording a better Commodity, as well he may, having several Opportunities which the small Brewer has not, of defraud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the King, and every other Person he deals with therefore by that Advantage, and several other underhand Dealings, as that of their appearing in full Bodies at the Markets after their own Granaries are full, pretending to give and offer great Rates, purely to inhance the Price upon the poor Brewer, who can buy no more then from Hand to Mouth, therefore with all the Toyl of Body and Mind he takes, only bustles himself into his own Confusion, without the least prospect of Advantage; for if he chance to get a good Customer, even in that the Chilhood of his Fortune is too forward to be long-liv'd, being pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sued like a Bird that has got a Prey, all other Birds of Prey are running to take it from him: But till some Expedient be sound out for their Release, they must; still choak themselves with the Husks, whilst the great Brewers feed comfortably upon the Kirnel; who are not satisfied with that, nor their own Abundance, but like <hi>Ahab,</hi> coveting poor <hi>Naboth</hi>'s Vineyard, are in pursuit, by their Warrants, of great numbers of their Trade, under a Pretence
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:98672:7"/>that their Charter can Justify their Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings; which extends yet to a greater piece of Cruelty: for whilst they slie from their Power, the great Brewer breaks in upon their Trade, and bribes and takes all their Customers away from them; and the next piece of inhumanity is, to cause the Victualler to Confess a Judgement of all he is worth, upon the Credit of which he serves him afresh, and lays the small Brewer, after the loss of his Trade and Debts, as low as the Hand of an entire Ru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ine can throw him; in which sad Condi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion he is rendred uncapable of seeking Relief, being indeed more fill'd with Consi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration of the Unhappiness, then thoughts of a Remedy. And all these evil Practi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces are in a great measure committed, to Impose upon the Parliament, who they would fain make believe, that it is the dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragment of the Times, and their lay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing on Taxes, that caused them to give over, when they, poor Creatures, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to to the old Proverb, must needs go when the Devil drives. And as for their Charters, which they value themselves so much upon, or Meeting at their Hall, I never could learn that any Grievance was redressed by them in the Trade, but much the contrary; for those that go with that Hope and Design, are serv'd like the silly Sheep in a Storm, who going to the Bramble
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:98672:8"/>for shelter, is still forced to leave its Fleece behind. But since they will be for de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroying the Kings Duty, and will admit of no other Competitor, I hope they will continue of the same good Humor that Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple do who gather Roses, are content to prick their Fingers too, tho' it would be much more the Interest of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to have the Trade in several Hands; for our daily Experience shews us, that ever a State flourishes best when Wealth is more equally spread, but as they are suffered to make themselves Parties, and lean to a Side, it is like a Boat o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verset by an uneven Weight: for the Brewer that has too small a Trade, wants Feathers to flie withal, whilst he that has too much, is but incumbred with too large a Tale; so where the Channel is too small for the Flood, who can wonder at the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verflowing and splendid Greatness of the Brewer. Tho' I must confess, it's a plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sant thing to see our Vine flourish, but let it alone and it soon destroys it self with superfluous Branches: But I humbly hope, the Tax which I plead for, will not only prune that to Advantage, but also be found to be a much more advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tageous and equal Tax than ever yet has been Propos'd in the Brewing Trade; but till we have tried both, Ignorance can ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver be known to be Ignorance till it be
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:98672:8"/>matcht with Knowledge, after which I humbly hope you will ever allow him to be the most competent Judge, that has been the best Practitioner. But tho' we miss'd the Mark in laying on a genernal Tax upon Malt, and also upon strong Beer and Ale, yet we by our Disappointment in that Case, ought not to be discouraged from still searching for the right Vein; There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore in order to our finding it, and to keep our Profits still in Motion, we should do with our Taxes, as Musitians use to do with those that Dance too long, as some are taken off, others should be brought on: And in this Case, sure none so fit to Dance as those that Fortune Pipes to. But being not willing to tire your Attention, or lengthen your Expectations, I shall now spread and lay before you a new invented Net to catch the Profits of the Brewing-Trade in, and let loose those that are not yet come to their full Growth. In or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to which, and to Levy this Tax, 'tis humbly Proposed, That every Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er that Brews above eighty Barrels of common Ale <hi>per</hi> Week, shall for every Barrel above that number pay the King One Shilling Additional Excise, besides what he paid before; which he may ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry well do, when he can under the same Charge of Rent and Servants Wages, Brew four times the Quantity the small Brewer
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:98672:9"/>do's, with this Advantage also, of being able to draw, by reason of the bigness of his Grist, as I said before, half a Barrel of Ale more of each Quarter of Malt; which if the great Brewer, can be sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfied with Brewing such a Quantity with their Beer Brewings, which we rec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kon a good living Trade, this Tax will no way reach 'em; but every Brewer that is by his Interest put upon exceeding that Quantity of eighty Barrels, is unde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niably his own Carver, and charges him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>self with this Tax as he pleases, without the least compulsion; so this Tax must be indisputably equal. But if the above-mentioned Reasons be not sufficient, I hope this will leave no room for Objection, when we consider, that the Brewers have by the fall of Malt alone, besides that of other things belonging to their Trade, at least Six shillings and two pence <hi>per</hi> Barrel Profit more then he expected, or had last Year; which I will soon prove by this Rule: That as Malt is fallen, tho' not yet at the lowest, from Fourty five Shillings to Twenty eight Shillings, which is Seventeen Shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter lower in Price then it was last Year, and the Quantity of Ale drawn off each Quarter being two Barrels and three Fourths; so the Seventeen Shillings by the fall of Malt divided upon two Barrels and three Fourths,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:98672:9"/>makes Six Shillings and two pence of an Additional Profit upon each Barrel to them, over and above their first un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reasonable and settled Gains, tho' the Drink continues still at the same Price that they thought fit to raise upon it, to suit the Extremity of the Times, and to answer the Malt Tax, which they never fail in such Cases in doing double; how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever that, and the cheapness of their Hops, Coals and Cask, we take no notice of in the abovementioned Six Shillings and two pence, Tho' out of those Profits that stands neglected, they may very well af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford to pay the King such a Sum as may answer the Tax of One Shilling upon a Barrel.</p>
            <p>It is further humbly Propos'd, That every Barrel of Stout and Double Beer, or Double Ale, and likewise your <hi>Derby.</hi> Ale and <hi>Nottingham</hi> Ale, and all them sorts of Drink Brew'd by the common Brewer, and shall Exceed the Price of Twenty Shillings <hi>per</hi> Barrel, shall also pay the King Four Shillings and Nine Pence <hi>per</hi> Barrel Additional Excise, besides what it paid before; for this Reason, that all such Double Drinks, the Brewer, by hav<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Forty Shillings, and Five Pounds <hi>per</hi> Barrrel, has double and treble Price from the Buyer for it, and paying the King but single Duty, has therefore such monstrous
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:98672:10"/>Profits, that they Brew ten times a grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Quantity then they ever use to do of those sorts of strong Liquors, purely to defraud the King of his Excise; which they too often practice in several other Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spects, as that of conveying great Quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tities of their Worts in Barrels their Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Nights, to their Tap-houses and Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctullers Ce<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ars, which still lie so near and convenient, that they can with the great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>est ease imaginable, shift those Worts in their Tun again for Drink that is through<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly wrought, having their Centine's out to watch the Gaugers coming and going, who can miss nothing, by reason he finds as many Barrels broke in as they have taken out, so consequently must find the Tun still at the same Inch; where I shall at present leave it, and proceed to the Breathing another Vein, which I am sure will conduce much to the Welfare, and levelling the Profits of the Trade. In order to which, and to help to Levy this Tax.</p>
            <p>'Tis farther humbly Proposed, That every Brewer that Brews your common Hopt and Guile Beer, shall for every such Barrel pay the King Two Shillings over and above the Duty paid before; for this Reason, that because the strength the Hop adds to it, he draws a Barrel more of each Quarter of Malt then he does of
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:98672:10"/>Ale, and sells this Barrel and fourth part of a Barrel, for One Pound five shillings out to the Victualler, or One Pound ten shillings if he keeps it a while in his Store-house; and this Barrel and fourth part of a Barrel which he draws extraordinary, he pretends he must do to answer the Charge of the Hop, tho all People that understand any thing of the Brewing-Trade, are sensible; that the utmost: Quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tity of Hops that goes to four Barrels of Beer, which is the Product of a Quarter of Malt; never exceeds Eight pounds of Hops, if even without the deceit of using Wormwood, they imbitter'd their Drink with Hop alone, which they never do; so as Hops are now fallen from Fourteen to Six pounds a Hundred, this Eight pound of Hops cost no more at that Rate then Seven shillings and Eleven pence, and the Barrel and fourth part which is drawn, for that Reason being sold out of their Store-house for One pounds ten shillings; by which we may see what a Conscion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able use they make of every Pretence they are furnished with. And to make all things clear, that no room may be left for Misconstruction, I shall lay before you the real Profits and Charge that attend the Brewing every Quarter of Malt that is Brew'd for that Inriching Commodity of Hopt and Guile Beer.</p>
            <pb n="20" facs="tcp:98672:11"/>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>In the First place, a Quarter of Malt, Price</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Eight pound of Hops at the Price of 6 <hi>l. per.</hi> Hundred</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>7</cell>
                     <cell>11</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>For the Excise of four Barrels of Beer, which is the clear Product of a Quarter of Malt, after the Allowance they have of three Barrels in every Twenty three at the Excise Office, which re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duces the Four shillings and Nine pence to Four shillings and Three half pence <hi>per</hi> Barrel,</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>For the Proportion of Firing belonging to that Quarter of Malt, as Coals go now,</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="total">Total</cell>
                     <cell role="total">2</cell>
                     <cell role="total">13</cell>
                     <cell role="total">6</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>Three Chaldron of Coals being suffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent to Brew Sixty Quarters of Malt to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, for when the Copper is once set on boiling, a small matter keeps it still sim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pering on.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Now for what the above mention'd Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of Malt makes and yields the Brewer, out of which he has nothing
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:98672:11"/>to pay but that Days proportion of House-rent and Houshold Charges, which is so inconsiderable, that it is infinitely made more then sufficient Provision by the dexterity of his nimble and Eagle-eyed Servants, whose Business is chiefly to outwit the Gan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Product and Price of the Drink drawn of a Quarter of Malt, if sold out immediatly to the Victualler, —</p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Four Barrels of strong Beer at Twenty shillings <hi>per</hi> Barrel,</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>For the proportion of Yeast, Wash and Blew Jack, which is, a Term they have for the bitter small Beer,</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="total">Total</cell>
                     <cell role="total">4</cell>
                     <cell role="total">6</cell>
                     <cell role="total"> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Charge of the Malt, Coals, Hops, and Excise,</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Brewers clear Gains of each Quarter of Malt,</cell>
                     <cell>1</cell>
                     <cell>12</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>The Product and Price of the Drink drawn from a Quarter of Malt, if kept two or three Months by the Brewer in his Store-house.</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:98672:12"/>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="label"> </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>l.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>s.</hi>
                     </cell>
                     <cell role="label">
                        <hi>d.</hi>
                     </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>Four Barrels of Stale Beer at One pound four shillings <hi>per</hi> Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rel,</cell>
                     <cell>4</cell>
                     <cell>16</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>For that Quarter of Malt, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion of Yest, Wash and Blew-Jack,</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                     <cell> </cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell role="total">Total</cell>
                     <cell role="total">5</cell>
                     <cell role="total">2</cell>
                     <cell role="total"> </cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>
               <table>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Charge of the Malt, Coals, Hops and, Excise,</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>13</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Brewers clear Gains of each Quarter of Malt, if he allows the Drink two or three Months Cellaridge, besides Granes, which I reserve to touch upon in a more proper place.</cell>
                     <cell>2</cell>
                     <cell>8</cell>
                     <cell>6</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The clear Profit and Gains of the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tire Brewing of Sixty Quarters of Malt, at the Rate of One pound Twelve shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Six pence Profit upon each Quarter, if Sold out immediately to the Victualler,</cell>
                     <cell>97</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                     <cell>The Brewers clear Profit and Gains of the intire Brewing of Sixty Quarters of Malt, if they Sell it out of the Store-house at the Rate of Two pound eight shillings
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:98672:12"/>and six pence Profit upon each Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter,</cell>
                     <cell>145</cell>
                     <cell>10</cell>
                     <cell>00</cell>
                  </row>
               </table>
            </p>
            <p>And those Profits every Week repeat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, besides double and treble the Quantity of Malt Brew'd also every Week for Ale, h what has insensibly rais'd and inabl'd several Brewers to lay out Fifty or Six<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty thousand pounds in Purchasing Estates in less then Fifteen or Sixteen Years standing, which, together with several Thousand pounds <hi>per Ann.</hi> still coming in by their Trade, or more or less in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion to what they Brew, may I think, from the Drays side, be reckon'd a very happy Remove, for those that Wet such a Quantity as Two or Three hundred Quarters <hi>per</hi> Week, which is none of the greatest Brewers of all, must therefore, as you may see by the abovemention'd Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putation, have several Hundreds of pounds <hi>per</hi> Week clear Profit; which is so vast a thing, that nothing besides the daily repetition of such Profits, and quick and sudden Returns, could without a Miracle work such Wonders. But I know it will be Objected by the Brewer that gets those Several Hundreds <hi>per</hi> Week, That it's not all clear Gains, by reason 'tis incident to Losses and Casualties, by the Breaking and
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:98672:13"/>Running away of Customers. But that Objection is soon answer'd, since they have by ingrosing all the Trade in their own Hands, pickt and cull'd their Customers so well, that after Breaking so many small Brewers, and Joyning the best of their Trade to their own, therefore refuse to Serve any desperate Customers; by which means they have made their Profits safe, as well as great.</p>
            <p>It may perhaps likewise be Objected, That I made in my Computation no mention of the Charge of House-rent, Horse-keeping, or Servants Wages; but if I did not then, I will now, rather then leave them any Loophole to creep out of; Allow the Brewer out of those several Hundreds a Week, Fifteen pounds to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swer Losses and Charges of that Nature, which I am sure is more then the Case requires.</p>
            <p>But having already shewed too much to leave the rest disguised, I shall lay be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore you several other Advantages they have over the small Brewers, as well as defrauding those they deal with. In the first place, the small Brewer and new Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginner being forc'd at the full Standard Measure to buy all his Barrels new from the Cooper, therefore gives at least Two shillings worth of his Drink more to the Buyer then the great Brewers do, by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:98672:13"/>their Barrels being old and broken Chind, fall short by the Paring and Cob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, and setting the Heads lower at least four Gallons in every Barrel; and not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withstanding this, that Brewer is reckon'd a Saint that sends them more then Three parts full, cover'd with a Clay Cap to any Person of Quallity, or private Gentleman's House, by which they tickle to think they make the Duty of Excise rebound back, and fall upon the Parliament them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves.</p>
            <p>And as for the poor Victualler, who of choice takes in no more then his Barrel three parts full, to leave room for work<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out, and save the loss that other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise they may sustain by Jolting it upon the Dray, therefore keeps a nine-Inch Gauge, to Gauge the dry part of the Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rel, supposing to pay no more then for the wet Inches; but the Brewers Servants having a Trick for all things (as they boast themselves,) instead of filling the Drink to reach the Gauge, they find a way to let the Gauge reach the Drink, by shaving off and planing all the Wood about the Bunghole of the Barrels, which is general<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly so very thick that it keeps the Gauge a great distance from the Drink, but af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter being pair'd, the silly Victualler by reaching the Drink with it, supposes he has his due, when indeed by that means
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:98672:14"/>he wants a Shilling at least in every Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rel of it: Therefore the most inconsider<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able piece of Fraud they are guilty of, is sufficient to make provision for this Tax. But the poor Victualler does not come of so; for the Dray-men, who it seems are not reckon'd qualified for their Places, except they carry a good sharp Knife with them, whips off assoon as the Victualler turns his Back (as they brag themselves) at least an Inch more of the Knot upon the Handle of his Gauge, which makes the Gauge, which was before but nine Inches, by that means Ten; so they lose, poor Creatures, by the first and last Cheat at least Two shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings in a Barrel, for the more dry Inches he has, the fewer wet ones will serve, and seems so well pleased with his Measure, that the Dray-man must have a Pot too for his good Service in the Bargain: So when the Brewers Art and Riddle is unfolded, the Wonder touching the suddain Rise of them will not be long liv'd, And having, I hope, even to Demonstration convinc'd you of the Frauds of the Brewers, and like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise the impossibility of the small ones subsisting under the same Tax, except it be lay'd on so, as the just Cure may an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swer the particular Disease, and also ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to the giving of Incouragment, and Grains of Allowance to several Persons, who only wait for it to re-inhabit those
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:98672:14"/>great numbers of Brew-houses lately put down by the Oppression of the great Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, provided they can be protected and freed from the Penalty of their Charters; and in my humble Opinion, some regard should be had to them: For the first rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing and Establishing a Trade, is like that of Planting a Wood, by which a man must lose several Years Rent, and have his Reward at the last; after which, lay what Tax You will, it hurts him not; for like a quick-set Hedge, the more you Pare and take from him, the better he still Thrives and Flourishes, having an Opportunity of fixing it double upon the Buyer; but I hope in this Case he will not streach his Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>science so far upon Tender-Hooks, as to pretend to it at this time of Day, since he may by the fall of every thing that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs to his Trade, afford them a consi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derable abatement too; tho I believe the Victualler will scare trouble him for it, since he has been forc'd to raise his Drink from Two pence to Three pence and a Groat a Pot; so let the Brewer pretend what he will, it's a Jest to think that any besides the Consumer pays the Tax: there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the World, I think, must needs be astonish'd and suprised to see so Rich a Treasure allowed them upon such easie and advantagious Terms as are herein mention'd.</p>
            <pb n="28" facs="tcp:98672:15"/>
            <p>But if by any unskilful Discerner of their Profits, we are imposed or prevailed upon to take other Measures, and the great Brewer suffered thus to pack <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Cards, their Profits will still turn up Trumps, let who will be the Loser; for those Birds of prey never want Beasts of Burden to pack their uneasie Luggage upon; so that in all their Managment the great Brewer, I think, much resembles the Ant, who is a wise Creature for her self, but a very shrow'd thing in an Orchard or Garden. And indeed the Rich Brewer is no less de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>structive to waste the Publick, and also that decayed part of the Trade which it still preys upon, without considering that cannot be wounded but through the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernments side, who the small Brewer is in proportion as good a Benefactor to as the Rich, tho not so to his Family, whose Condition is so different from that of the great Brewers, that one Surffets as 'twere with the excess of Plenty, while the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Starves; but by their own Declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion they cannot help that growing Evil of being Rich, though they seek all means possibly to avoid it; for People, they say, come very hardly by small Riches, but very easily by great Treasures, for these reasons:</p>
            <p>That when a Mans stock comes to that, that he can command the Price of Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kets,
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:98672:15"/>and overcome those Bargains which for their greatness are few Mens Mony, he therefore runs up his Fortune so insen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sibly, that lay what Tax you will upon him it hurts him not, provided it affects those also that go no sharers with him in the Profits; for upon the Destruction of the small Brewers is still raised the Fortune of the great Ones. But this Tax will not only scape those that go no Sharers in the Gains, but single out things so well as to catch the Profits of the Trade fast by the Throat, as I shall make appear.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>First,</hi> the Duty of One shilling <hi>per</hi> Barrel upon Ale cannot yet extend to the small Brewer, by reason he is not so happy as to Brew half so great a Quantity as Eigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Barrels <hi>per</hi> Week, tho upon those advangious Terms he would gladly pay tre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble that Sum; but a Tax laid on after any other manner makes no distinction, but hur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries Profits and Loss into the same Current together. And Secondly, the Duty of Four shillings and nine pence upon Stout passes his Door, because that still is made of the first Running of those very great quanti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of Malt Brewed by the topping Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, which he cannot attain to. And Third<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, that Tax of Two shillings <hi>per</hi> Barrel upon Hopt and Guile Beer, do's but slight<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly touch him, for the Rreasons I urg'd be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore,
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:98672:16"/>being not able to give the Credit that is required, or Brew much of that in rich<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Commodity, which indeed is the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sterpiece of the Trade, and by which they make several Hundreds <hi>per Cent</hi> in a Year of their Money; so that we put our Mis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fortunes upon a thousand Causes, whilst the real one escapes our Censure; for I will make it appear, that it is the Monopolizing the Trade, and not the Tax, nor any other Cause, that ever injures it: As for Example, sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pose we allow the small Brewer, who wets such a Quantity as 20 Quarters of Malt <hi>per</hi> Week, a Pound upon each Quarter Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit to defray his Houshold Charges, and suppose the great Brewer, who Brews such a Quantity as 300 Quarters <hi>per</hi> Week, has but Ten shillings out of each Quarter Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit, yet you see, notwithstanding the small Brewers double Price, the great Brewers 300 Ten shillings, tho seemingly less Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit, makes a difference of at least 130 <hi>l.</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween his Getings and that of the small Brewers, whose House-Rent and Charges being within a small matter the same; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it not only eats up that seeming Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits, but destroys his quick Stock too; by which you may see the great Brewers Riches, like <hi>Homers</hi> Verses, has a slide and easiness more then the Verses of other Poets: there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore we may be satisfied, that it's quantity and not quality that do's good here: But
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:98672:16"/>tho in the above mentioned Computation I nam'd 300 Ten shillings, I am sure so many Pounds is a more real Representati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of their Weekly Profits, which the small Brewer has no comfortable relish of, by reason of the smallness of his Trade: But a Tax laid on upon all the Ale that's Brew'd above Eighty Barrels <hi>per</hi> Week, will not only set all Persons already con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd upon an equal Footing, but also in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courage hundreds of People to come to re-inhabit those Brew-houses that are shut up, finding they shall not be liable to this Tax till their Trade is raised and settled; otherwise, whilst they lie under the same Tax, a Man may by striving to raise a Trade, soon sink himself; for we may as reasonably expect Rent out of a House before its finish'd, as Profits out of a Trade before its Establish'd, especi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally while the great Brewers have such vast advantages over them: For we may with the same possibility expect, that a little Child of Five Years old should carry an equal share of a Burden proportion'd to the strenth of a Man of Thirty, as the small Brewer to bear up under a Tax of that nature of the Malt-Tax with the great Brewer. But to level the inequa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity for the future; we should in this Case follow the Example and Conduct of a Wise and Politick Prince, who thinks, if he
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:98672:17"/>cannot strengthen himself, yet if lie wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kens His Enemy, He has put his affairs in a happy Posture; which the same Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sures taken here, will soon cause the Trade to have the same lustre all over, and disperse those Heaps that like Muck does most good when spread: Tho per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps the great Brewers, or their Friends for them, may Object, that this is an im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>practicable way of Levying a Tax; but since there's no other Means left, and that every Age grows wiser, we ought not, in my humble Opinion, to reverence a gray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>headed Error so far, as to let it sway to the untimely prejudice of so just and equal a Tax. But if we, notwithstanding any po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing Argument against it, can be so for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunate as to close with this Resolution, it would be the happiest Victory that ever this Honorable House gain'd over them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves in a Business of this Nature, if it please God to unite their Opinions, and by it, Love to Posterity, the charitable Praise that's due to the happy Instruments of preserving the Poor, and pulling down those evil Customs that has hitherto prov'd so pernicious to us to us; after which the great Brewer will not lie under the Scandal and Curse of defrauding the King, or destroy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Poor, but have sufficient still to live up to the highest Pitch of Quality: For those that have Sea-room enough, can
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:98672:17"/>make any Wind serve, and I am sure, let it blow which way it will, they'll gain the Point they aim at; for it is a Mistake to think the great Brewer will ever lessen his Profit by any Tax, but on the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary be Gainers thereby, and make the like Profit by the Moneys they lay out on the account of the Tax, as they do în proportion of the Money they lay out on the account of several other Materials they use in their Imployments; for this to them is a sort of Material, let the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament reckon how they please, they make no other Reckoning then this; so much Money laidout, no matter on what, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther for the Tax, or for buying of Malt, Coals, Hops, so much must come in ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to their accustomed Profits, one way or other they will be sure to make their Profits or Gain come safe home, and answer their usual Return, with an overplus, always alledging to those to whom they sell their Goods, how heavy the Tax lies on 'em, when indeed they place it double upon the Buyer, instance the raising their Hopt and Guile Beer last Winter from Eigteen to Twenty shillings extraordinary, to answer the Tax of Four shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter, besides cutting their Measures, and raising their small Beer,
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:98672:18"/>by which, together with the Badness of it, they have almost starved the Poor; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore any Man may without Spectacles see great Brewers are still Gainers by every Tax that's laid upon them, though out of Cunning they seem to make a heavy sputter, and upon every such Occasion still run, like Pick-pockets in a Crowd, crying, Hold Thief, to keep up the ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Cry with those that really suffer: But that dull banter being worn Thread<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bare, all their Allegations will soon flie as a Mist before the cleer Beams of Truth, when their Profits are pointed at by those who know where they lie as well as them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves; so if they carved out so large a share then, what must they do now, when most things belonging to their Trade are fallen near half in half, nay some come down much lower, instance, that of Hops falling from Fourteen to five or six pounds a Hundred, and Malt from For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty five to Twenty seven and eight shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings <hi>per</hi> Quarter, and likewise expected suddenly to fall as low as a Pound, and also Barrels fallen from Three pounds Ten shillings a Last to Fourty eight shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings <hi>per</hi> Last, and Coals as cheap again as they were; therefore I know not for my life how we can avoid taking notice of so great and visible a Change, tho we seek all means possible to avoid the di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scovery.
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:98672:18"/>But tho the Brewers have by those Transports hitherto blinded their own Eyes, they ought not to dim the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments any longer, with hopes of the suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cess of making such Monstrous Profits so ever to escape the Tax, but rather sure thi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> themselves very favourably dealt by, and own that the Kings Duty ought to be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected out of the Profits, and not loss of a Trade; and when things are so set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, the small Brewers, whose hopes hitherto have had but very weak incourag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments to aspire at, will go on with all the Chearfulness imaginable, and soon bring his Face out of that shrunken, wooden Posture, which the Brow-beating of the great Brewers contracted it to, and after such a Deliverance will freely contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bute to paying his share of any Tax the Parliament shall think sit to lay upon 'em, provided they can be admitted to enjoy their Liberty and Properties equal to those who now Usurp an Authority over them; which the small Brewer thinks very hard▪ being all free-born Subjects, and as good Benefactors in proportion to the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment as they Caii pretend to. And this manner of proceeding will not only Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel the in equality; and stop the grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing evils of the Trade; but also bring greater and safer Returns to our Cossers, then possibly could be expected by any
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:98672:19"/>duplicate
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:98672:19"/>duplicate
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:98672:20"/>other Measres we could have taken; for before, by laying a general Tax, we put the King's Duty in the Balance against Losses and Mifortunes, but here they are <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ut in the Scale against Prodigious Profits of over-grown Brewers, which far over balances them and all reasonable Gettings; so seeing the equality and necessity of lay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing this Tax on, we may if we please from this day forward, date a happy change in the Condition of the Brewing Trade; and even those great Brewers have still encouragment enough to pay Homage to the Charms of their Profits and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trest, whatever they may pretend to the contrary: For there is no reason that those Blessings daily shower'd down upon us, should be received by them alone, without letting the least drop spatter to refresh that decay'd part of the Trade, of in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crease the Growth of the Kings Duty, at a time that the Government stands so much in need of Mony, and on the Contrary, whole tides of prosperity swimming in eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Channel towards the Brewers, by the fall of every thing belonging to their Trade, and the rise of Drink, which they never fail upon the remotest appearance of a Tax, of charging double upon the Buyer. So it is a clear Case, that let the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment charge what Tax they will, they are resolved, by having an equal share, to
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:98672:20"/>measure length of Purses for ever with the Government. Now that I have shew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed you the reasonableness of laying on this Tax upon Stout, Hopt and Guile Beer▪ I shall endeavour to make the certainty of its answering our expectation in every Particular appear, by demonstrating, that the Third part of all the Drink in the Kingdom is that sort of Hopt and Guile Bee; for every third Brewing that's brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed is that sort of Drink, otherwise in draw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that and Ale together, it cannot with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the third parts being Beer, be a proper Mixture, and when that is joined with the prodigious Quantities of Stout, and those sorts of <hi>Nottingham, Darby,</hi> and other strong Ales, they must needs I am sure turn the scale against what Common Ale is brewed in the Kingdom; consequently therefore half the Drink brewed by the Common Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er will be liable to this Tax of Two shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and four and nine pence <hi>per</hi> Barrel, besides that of One shilling <hi>per</hi> Barrel up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on all the Quantities of Ale brewed a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove Eighty Barrels <hi>per</hi> Week; so by this means nothing can escape us but what's better lost then found. But I deem it need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>less by multiplying words, to make things plainer, since the Commissioners of Excise can by their Books and Weekly Return of the several sorts of Drink, make so ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sie and fair a Cmputation as shall suffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ently
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:98672:21"/>convince this Honourable House of the Truth of what I say, touching the raising, or rather Exceeding the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned Sums, not without hopes also of future Benefits to the Government as the Trade still flourishes and increases, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sides this Consideration, which I hope will render this Tax more preferable then any other, being free of that Charge that strikes deep by the Salary of Officers in most other Funds; but this being under the cognizance of the Excise Officers, they may, with the assistance of one or two Commissioners more added to the Set, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive this with the rest of the Duty of Excise, which is an advantage we are de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stitute of in any other Tax, by reason we generally lose, besides their Salaries, great part at first by the Ignorance of new Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, as I am sure we have also done in the Duty of Excise by the oversights of unexperienced Projectors wrong place<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing it, by whom you might perhaps have several suspicions touching those matters confirmed to your belief, but they could not by any unconcern'd Person be fussici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ently grounded to seize your Judgment; but if my humble Advice be thought ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viceable or axcepted, it shall I hope for the future prove a very hard Task for the Brewer to impose upon the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment: But by Taxing the superfluous
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:98672:21"/>Weekly quantities of Ale, and also that of Stout and Guile Beer, we are forc'd, purely to avoid dashing upon greater In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conveniences, to propose the laying this Tax after a triangle manner; but since a Three-corner'd Sum will not answer the Importunity of our Needs, I have yet a Reserve left to make it a good square one, out of a Fund that's never to be exhaust<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, therefore I hope deserves to be esteem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed before several Funds that only answer a short and single necessity; but this I will presume to say, will be thought necessary to continue even by future Ages, when things are made so clear and evident to Reason, as not only to bring us in by this Branch One hundred thousand Pound, but also save us double that Sum which goes out of the Kings Duty yearly by Frauds; but if by this means they can be prevent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, we reckon a Peny saved is a Peny got, for those former Tricks they can never practice to advantage after this Tax, which like a Looking-glass, will to the Kings Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers discover at first sight the least piece of Fraud the Brewer can be guilty of, and shall through the Cobweb disguise of all his honest pretensions, see the Spider infusing its venom: And I humbly hope, this Duty that I am going to plead for, shall appear to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> have all the property of the most valuable, equal and just Tax that can be
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:98672:22"/>wisht or desired for, especially since the Persons who contribute to it, have by wresting the power from the Parliament, raised this Tax themselves, therefore have made the Government a good pretension to share of it; not that I think the Tax was ill plac'd, had it been done by pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perer Hands; but from whatsoever cause our Happiness springs, we ought not to be a little proud of our good Fortune, especially when it is heapt upon us by tho. Hands of the fair Sex, the Brewers Ladies I mean, who to increase their Pin-Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, rais'd their Tax last Month upon the Buyer of their Granes, cunningly alledging, they must do so to enable them to pay the Tax which they expect will be laid upon them, to answer the deficiency of the Malt Tax: And since they are so good at Jesting, and so merrily inclin'd, in my humble Opinion they ought in such a case to be banter'd with a matter of Truth, and be allow'd the applause of good de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signing subjects; for had the most sincere Friend the Government has, work'd his Brains and studied to the Age of <hi>Methu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selah,</hi> he could not have thought of a more equal or advantageous Tax in proportion then this; for besides the raising One hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred thousand Pound, it will infallibly save the King, as I said before, double that Sum, by preventing the Frauds of Brewers, who
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:98672:22"/>after this will be morally impossible for to wrong the King of Five shillings in a whole year, without the pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="5 letters">
                  <desc>•••••</desc>
               </gap> of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cise Officers; for this reason, that when the Gaugersare commanded to Gauge the Mash-Tuns as well as Drink-Tuns, and make their weekly Entry of it, they will there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore by Gauging the Granes, know to a hanful how many Quarters of Malt has been wet that Brewing; by which Rule, and knowing that two Barrels and three parts of a Barrel is the Product and length that is drawn from any Quarter of Malt for Ale, and Four full Barrels for strong Beer, they can by that Rule therefore miss, if they convey but five Gallons of their Worts away, tho' they could not be ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pable of doing so at times when they have Carried off perhaps twenty or thirty Barrels of a Brewing Night to their Tap-houses and Victuallers Cellars; but if those Measures are taken, it will quickly spoil their sport in that Case: And as for take<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out any of the Granes to deceive the Gaugers, that's altogether impossible to be done, except they could find out some Art to banish the Tell-tale Light, which shows any Officer with half an Eye if they touch but one spoonful of those Granes, by reason after the Worts run off, there lies on the top of the Granes, a conjeal'd Scum, which covers it all over as thick and as
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:98672:23"/>smooth as a sheet of Lead, which is never to be touch'd till the Buyer of those Granes comes▪ to take them away, other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise were they not lockt up as 'twere by that Scum, the Buyer, who takes 'em the whole year round, will never believe they have half their due; and this same thick Covering may as well defend our Right.</p>
            <p>Having now, I hope, made you sensi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble how constant and faithful a Card this Tax will prove to the Duty of Excise, beyond that of any Watch or Morning-Man, I shall now endeavour to make the certainty of its answering your Expectation in every Particular appear, by this Rule, That if Four shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter upon malt was supposed to raise Four hundred thousand pounds <hi>per Ann.</hi> by the same Rule we may expect from One shilling <hi>per</hi> Quarter upon Granes, One hundred thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand pounds <hi>per Ann.</hi> but considering the Frauds that several Malsters themselves own to me of being guilty of, we may I am sure reasonably hope, that this Tax will answer one half, if not more, of the Malt Tax, besides allowance given of what private House-keepers makes use of in their own Brewings; and I do not doubt but you will think my Belief is grounded upon Reason, when you consider, that not the least Handful of those Granes; if even they thought it worth their while, can
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:98672:23"/>escape the King Duty; but that piece of Fraud is impossible to be practised in this Case, Granes being a Commodity that taints in a few hours, therefore without the search of an Officer will soon discover themselves, if hid: But in the Malt Tax I am satisfied we have been sufficiently imposed upon, even to the loss of the Third part of the Duty; and that Mischief was attended by a Train of others to the Buyer, who found his Malt all this last Year Steely and hard Barly, by reason the Malster, to save the Duty, never af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forded it half Flowring enough, but watch'd all opportunities to hoist it away, and clap fresh upon the Flower and Kiln instead of it against the Officers came; which did so but seldom, but the Tax upon Granes we are satisfied will come to attend the rest of the Duty of Excise, and conduct it all safe home to our Coffers, no Person having the least design upon them. And the Second Advantage is, that this Tax being under the Cognisance also of the same Officers of Excise, it may therefore be without the least Charge brought in Weekly and Monthly with the Duty of the same Drink that's drawn from those several Parsels of Granes, which will be as good as a Rule to the Commissioners to measure the Honesty of the Gaugers by, when the Duty of every Brewing and
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:98672:24"/>Quarter of Granes comes in at the foot of the Bill charg'd upon the Drink drawn from it, which will be expected like the Nicks of a Tally to answer one another; for the Commissioners, and all People that understand any thing of the Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Affair, knows the quantity of Barrels that are generally drawn from every Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of Malt or Granes; which Measures, if Taken will be so great an aw upon the Gaugers, in whose power only it is now to hurt us, that they rarely will, I dare say, after this attempt to do it, tho all means failing, we may reasonably believe they will not want temptation in that Case; but to prevent any ill Design of that nature, it is absolutely necessary that both Duties should come under the considera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of one sort of Managers, which they may with the assistance of a Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioner or two more, do with the greatest case imaginable, this being not incident to the Misfortune that attends all other Taxes, in which we generally find the Evil grows proportionable as the Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tages rise; but this will be so far from that, that it not only brings its own Return safe home, but aso be a perfect Bulwark to defend the Duty of Excise: And though this One hundred thousand pounds <hi>per An.</hi> to that is but a small Edging, yet it will grove a very useful one in binding down
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:98672:24"/>and hemming in our former Profits, which have all this time been Ravell'd and wasted away for want of it. But for future pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vention, and to raise this Tax, its humb<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly proposed, That the Granes of every Quarter of Malt brew'd by the Common Brewer or Distiller, shall for every such Quarter pay the King One shilling; which tho hitherto they seem to be things of no Value, yet they will bring in a great Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venue, even without reducing the Brewers Wives to the necessity of Exchanging their <hi>Diamond Pins</hi> for those of the commoner sort: But that being too cruel and severe a Decree, we must yet pronounce a mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der Sentence of only going small sharers with those Ladies, who were it not for the Custom that's given them, would per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps, like <hi>Esep</hi>'s Cock, be happier, and much better pleased with a few Barly Corns, then with the richest <hi>Gems</hi> that now glit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters about 'em, it being as natural a Choice for one as the other. And now I shall shew you the Reasonableness, as well as the un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>speakable Service this sort of Tax will be to the Government: In order to which, it's fit this Honourable House should be made sensible of the vast Diffierence that is be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the Price of Granes now, and when they were first allow'd the Brewers Wives for Pin-Mony, being then sold at the highest for no more then Four pence half-penny
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:98672:25"/>a Quarter, tho Malt was then at the Price of Thirty shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter, and Ale fold for Fourteen and Sixteen shillings <hi>per</hi> Barrel; but having this several Years been drawing the Buyers consent by piece meales to raise them, and having brought them up to Twenty pence <hi>per</hi> Quarter this last <hi>September,</hi> which is a very reasonable thing to do at a time that Malt is considerably cheaper, and Drink extravagantly dearer; the consideration of which, backt with their own Argument and Banter, of expecting to make up the Deficiency of the Malt Tax, is I think sufficient to justify our Pretention to it, especially since it is a thing made so light of, as to be never e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>steemed nor brought to balance any rec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>koning of the Brewers; and that light O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pinion has this several Years sway'd to our prejudice, and caused them to escape the Duty hitherto.</p>
            <p>I suppose it may likewise be Objected, that this Duty may be a little too severe on the stragling Ale-houses in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, who Brew their own Drink, and give their Granes to their Cows and Hogs. For to make that easie, and having enough in <hi>London,</hi> and other great Towns to make 'em up with the Distillers Granes, our disioyn'd Sum, being out of danger of being imposed upon as we have been in the Malt Tax; it's therefore my humble O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pinion,
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:98672:25"/>that those Persons that Brew and sell there own Drink in the Country, ought if this Honourable House think fit, to pay no more then Six pence <hi>per</hi> Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, which they will no doubt reckon a very happy change, from that of being oblig'd to pay Four shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter to the Malt Tax, which has occasion'd a very sad outery in the Country: If any body will take the pains to cast things up they may soon find that those Granes of the great Price they have set upon them of late Years, brings the Brewers Wives for Pin-Mony, half as much as the whole Duty of Excise brings the King, allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ances for Frauds and Distillers Granes con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sider'd, several of them having a Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand and Fifteen hundred pounds a Year for theit Granes; which Encouragment, to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether with the glittering of their Jew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>els and splendor of their Equipage, would make any body, I think, fond of being a Brewers Wife. But least they should think this Tax should strike too deep, and cause a Palpitation in the Heart of those Funds that's reserv'd for greater Diversions, I shall, to banish all fears of that kind, make you sensible that this Tax will but slightly touch them, being paid by an able sort of People, who carry on very Inriching and gainful Trades, as Wood-mongers, Coal-mongers, Masters of Lame-Wharfes, Sca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vengers,
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:98672:26"/>Cow-keepers, Swinherds, and several Trades more, too numerous herein to be mention'd, and the chief Food of all those Cattle and Horses belonging to those several sorts of Trades, being Granes; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore we have especially here in <hi>London</hi> and other great Towns, forty Buyers to one Seller, which causes 'em indeed to grow troublesome to the Brewer, striving who shall first Oblige 'em to take their Mony at any rate for those Granes: And in my humble Opinion, the working Horse, and the milch Cow that's daily bringing in the Peny, is better able to pay a Tax then several other Animals, who differ from them in nothing but the name of Man, and capacity of getting any thing like them by their Industry, to pay for their Heads, or any other Duty that falls to the share of so wretched a Condition. And the reason why I propose the placing this Tax so as it may extend to those Cattel, is purely to level the equality of the Duty between the Brewers Wives and them, and to save the charge that attends the Collecting of it, when divided into so many Channels; which Inconvenience we shall avoid now, by taking it up at the Mash-Tuns side or Fountain head. And as for what Agreement they have made for this Years Granes, let those Persons wran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gle that out with the Brewers Wives, Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gains
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:98672:26"/>of that nature among them being still like Jipsies Knots, fast and loose when they please; but I suppose, to make the Profit of their Granes equal to what it was the last Year, they will agree to bear it between 'em; for sure they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not in their own more serious and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward thoughts believe it a reasonable thing, that those Gentlemen and Members of Parliament, who have for so good a Cause and noble a Master, hitherto chearfully parted with a great share of their Estates, nay Tax'd their very Coach and Horses too, shall after the long continuance of so happy an Inclination, at last suffer their great Preservers Royal Word to lie at stake, for Sums that he has with Toyl of Body and Mind converted to our ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lasting Welfare, or by supplying him farther out of their Estates, take the Thorn out of another Man's Foot to thrust it into their own Heart, or a more sensible part of the Publick, which they have since this Revolution so generously and impartially done, that I hope every Person concern'd in this Tax, will after so noble a Precedent, not only cheerfully contribute to it, but also think them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves very favourably dealt by, in paying no more then for the bare Food of those Cattle which brings them in such great Profits Weekly: But having I think said
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:98672:27"/>enough to recommend this Tax to the Neces<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sity of the Government and Times, I shall now draw to a Conclusion; before which, to prevent the former Hardships that are put upon the Publick, by the Brewers plac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing every Tax double upon the Buyer, it's humbly proposed, that all the several sorts of Drinks sold by the common Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er for more then the Price they thought fit to raise upon it, when Malt was Four or Five and Forty shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter, shall pay double the within mention'd Tax, provided it exceeds the present Price of Drink, while Malt continues, or is sold under Forty shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter: But their being a far greater likelyhood of Malts falling to a Pound, the Brewer therefore will not be troubled with a Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty that's only Conditional. But this Tax having after being so long baffled, at last singl'd out things so well as to catch the Profits of the Trade fast by the Throat, we must thefore expect mighty Opposi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions and Strugglings against laying it upon the Drink after this manner; for the na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of the great Brewers and Profits are such, that while we place a Tax le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel upon the whole Trade, and leave 'em way to make their escapes, they will still prove Gainers by it; but being now met with at half-turn, they will, you'll see, like so many confined Cats, flie about and
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:98672:27"/>pester the Parliament with Petitions, which they never before thought their Intrest to do, knowing Silence was the best Orator, whilst they found the chief Burthen of every Tax fell undiscerned upon the small Brewer; for I am satisfi'd, they would be much better pleased to have all the Duty of Excise doubled up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the whole Trade, then be Oblig'd to pay the Tenth part of it after this Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, by reason the small Brewer, for whom it is impossible to subsist under the same Tax, would soon be forc'd to leave all to the great ones, who upon every such Occasion still watches, like People upon the Shore, hoping for a Shipwrack.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>